# **Matt Weber**

# **Senior Web Developer**

- O Hanover Park, Illinois, United States
- **\** +18472080035
- @ matt@awebersite.com
- www.linkedin.com/in/matthewoweber

### **SUMMARY**

My career began as a sales engineer and drafter in manufacturing, generating proposals, and maintaining engineering standards. Then, the company I worked for asked me to create a website for them. I had my own small business designing and implementing websites since college; what started as a hobby eventually became my career. I think my engineering background is perhaps my most important strength in that, at its core, all engineering is a recursive loop of strategic planning and data analytics with the ultimate goal of solving a complex problem by breaking it down into manageable pieces while continuously improving processes.

I have a coder's spirit, but because of my extensive non-coding skills and abilities, I ended up in several stakeholder or client-facing roles. Since my time as a writing tutor in high school, I have always gravitated towards writing and mentoring tasks. I have an exceptional technical writing ability which helps my written communications be clear and concise while managing a project or team.

My experience as an AutoCAD drafter and graphic designer have made me deft at generating visual aids, like flowcharts, when training staff or evangelizing a proposal. My greatest strength is being able to communicate well with both technical and business-leaning colleagues. I am a skilled instructor who has the patience and people skills to pass on my knowledge to others. Because my leadership skills are rooted in the concept of leading by example, I can inspire those around me to great success.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

October 2022-Current

#### Instructor

- 2U Trilogy
- Hanover Park, Illinois, United States

Teach online class called Full Stack Flex, which is a web development boot-camp style course leveraging Node.js, MongoDB ad React.js to build advanced web applications.

November 2021-October 2022

# Web Developer

- A Weber Site
- O Hanover Park, Illinois, United States
- Designed and built websites using a variety of platforms/frameworks, including WordPress and Django.
- · Consulted clients on web presence / brand management, including SEO and social media management.

#### Senior Web Developer

- The Catholic Charities of Chicago
- O Chicago, Illinois, United States
- Project management received/reviewed/approved design deck from branding vendor, consulted with stakeholders, created specs for development, generated work breakdown structures and timelines, assigned tasks across comms/IT/HR staff for implementation, orchestrated site-wide content audit/review/reorganization.
- Web development migrated/developed apps & business workflows from on prem to cloud platforms for finance/HR/IT/development, created/integrated platform modules as needed for all agency sites (in-house and vendor-hosted), setup/monitor analytics reporting.
- Special COVID projects created apps and workflows for daily employee surveys, senior administrator site visits and ad-hock tasks for COVID consultant.

July 2014-November 2019

#### Senior Database Administrator

- Chicago, Illinois, United States
- Data management ETL for data warehouse, clean/export/upload/verify data submissions for grant applications and to State and Federal social service agencies, migrate data, manage security groups and users.
- Software implementation prepare import files per vendor specification, setup/configure electronic medical records system, digitize EMRS assessments, train users.
- Database operations configure DB for mobile inventory app, backup data, perform database maintenance.
- Data reporting/SQL create and modify SSRS reports/datasets, merge records, clean/validate data, export sensitive data for legal requests.

January 2013-June 2014

#### Web/SharePoint Content Manager

- The Catholic Charities of Chicago
- Chicago, Illinois, United States
- Web development internet content development and full-stack management for all agency web properties, intranet content and app development, css/html support for communications/development operations.
- Special IT projects project manager for legal and finance dept. projects, feasibility research, requirements gathering, software demonstrations.
- Support management consolidated IT support desks, created IT knowledgebase, staff training, high priority ticket expediting.

April 2012-December 2013

# Web/MIS Support Specialist

- The Catholic Charities of Chicago
- Chicago, Illinois, United States
- Software support user experience discovery, testing, generate/publish documentation, software/process user training, gather requirements, demo creation, project research.

- Business intelligence agency form design and development using Adobe XFA forms, workflow analysis.
- Tier 1 and 2 user support operations –intake/triage/troubleshooting via phone and ticket software, review/file bugs, user experience surveying.

November 2008-November 2009

### **Content Developer**

- Galaxy Tool Supply
- Chicago, Illinois, United States
- Team management staff scheduling, task assignment, created/maintained product listings on multiple sites.
- Technical writing created/maintained/categorized products/technical specifications, wrote descriptions.
- Graphic design built photo booth, took/edited product photos for e-commerce/catalog sales applications.

April 2004-June 2007

## Manufacturing Engineer/IT Department

- **E** CSM Fastener Products Company
- Elk Grove Village, Illinois, United States
- Procurement designed custom/purchased standard tooling (open/solid dies, heading/threading/knurling dies) for cold heading/threading machines, managed tooling vendor relationships, resolved vendor issues.
- Webmaster/helpdesk designed/implemented/maintained company website, troubleshot all IT issues.
- Engineering maintained internal/industry/consensus part standards, produced/maintained manufacturing/sales AutoCAD/hand-drawn blueprints, created/maintained PPAP flow charts and FMEA matrices.
- Software development leveraged in-house parts coding system to create an automated quoting application, built inventory database for sales/warehouse operations, created utilities/calculators for sales/engineering.

### **EDUCATION**

1996-2001

#### **Bachelor of Science**

- Marquette University
- Milwaukee, Wisconsin, United States
- Computer Engineering

## **SKILLS**

IT Support	Documenta	ation Project	t Management	Content Dev	velopment	User Expe	erience	
Team Manag	ement St	aff Training	Form Design	Workflow An	alysis Sof	tware Imple	mentation	
Database Ma	nagement	Gather Requi	rements Sof	tware Develop	oment Coo	ding Gra	phic Design	
Data Reportir	na Busine	ess Intelliaence	Software Te	stina ETL	Data Ware	house	Sharepoint	HTML

CSS Javascript Django Wordpress React Photoshop JAVA UNIX SQL Server

Microsoft Power Automate Python Amazon Web Services PHP VS Code Node.JS REST Android

Adobe Illustrator Autocad SSRS Jquery Visual Studio C# .NET Mysql Postgresql AJAX

Power Bi Salesforce Adobe Premiere Indesign

### **LANGUAGES**

English - Fluent

# **WORK AUTHORIZATION**

I am authorized to work in the following countries:

United States